appliedlanguage.com 2018-09-02

# Privacy Policy - Capita Translation and interpreting

Capita Translation and Interpreting take care to protect the data privacy of our website users, and we comply with all relevant data protection legislation relevant to the UK. We will not share your information with third parties, or any company outside of the Capita Group, except if required to do so by law.

Below is some information on how we will use your data.

## Who is collecting your information?

We are Capita Translation and Interpreting. Our registered address is 17 Rochester Row, London, SW1P 1QT United Kingdom. Our postal address is Riverside Court, Huddersfield Road, Delph, Oldham, Greater Manchester, OL3 5FZ. If you wish to contact us, you can call +44 (0)845 367 7000 or email [DL-CTI-Marketing@capita.co.uk](mailto:DL-CTI-Marketing@capita.co.uk)

## What information do we collect?

The information which we collect and store during normal use of the site is used to monitor and analyse how parts of the site are used. Such use does not result in any personally identifiable data being collected or stored.

You have the option on certain pages within this site to submit personal information to Capita Translation and Interpreting in order that we might send you further information or contact you with regards to a request. To opt out of any email communications from us, please click the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the foot of the email in question.

Information we collect includes:

  * Questions, queries or information you submit, including your email address if you contact us via the website
  * If you apply to work with us as a freelance linguist, we will ask for personal details (including name, date of birth, payment rates, nationality) as well as employment history details (qualifications, experience, security clearance)
  * Your email address and subscription preferences when you sign up to our email alerts, and how you use our emails – for example whether you open them and which links you click on
  * Details of which version of web browser, device, network and operating system you used
  * Information on how you use the site, using cookies and page tagging techniques

## What do we do with your data?

We use the information we collect from you in a few different ways:

  * To improve the site by monitoring how you use it
  * To contact you with regards to your application as a freelance translator or interpreter for Capita Translation and Interpreting
  * To contact you about, or supply you with, a quote for a translation or interpreting request
  * In connection with any application, request or enquiry you make, your information will be passed directly to the relevant business unit or department within the group

By submitting your personal information through this website, you shall be consenting to it being processed in the manner described above by Capita Translation and Interpreting.

We do not transfer your data to servers based in countries outside of the EEA or the US.

### The legal basis for processing your data

The information we collect from linguists is necessary for the performance of a contract. If you are submitting data to request a quote you are consenting to us processing your data in order to fulfil your request.

### Sharing information

Your information will not be shared outside the Capita plc group of companies unless required by law.

### Data transfers

Your data may be processed with our Capita team in India or China both of which do not benefit from an adequacy decision made by the European Commission. To ensure that your data is provided with adequate protection, the processors have signed the European Standard Contractual Clauses.

## How long do we keep your data?

Up to 12 months after activity ceases.

## What if you do not want to provide information?

It is necessary for the performance of a contract and we cannot provide services if you do not provide this information

## Cookie Policy

We use cookies to improve your experience on our site. We use a minimal number of different cookies on our site. For more information about cookies, visit http://www.aboutcookies.org for detailed guidance.

The list below describes the cookies used on this site and what they are used for. Currently we operate an ‘implied consent’ policy which assumes that you are happy with this usage. If you are not happy with this policy, it is recommended that you delete the cookies, after having visited the site, or browse the site using your browser’s anonymous usage setting.

### First Party Cookies

These are cookies that are set by this website directly.

### Third Party cookies

Third Party cookies are set on your machine by external websites whose services are used on this site. For more information, check the respective policies of each of these sites to see how exactly they use information and to find out how to opt out, or delete, such information.

We usually use the following third party cookies:

  * Dotmailer – email distribution. For further information, please visit: <https://www.dotmailer.com/terms/privacy-policy/>
  * Google Analytics – website analytics
  * Google Remarketing – targeted advertising
  * Google Tag Manager – website analytics. For more information on Google’s privacy policy, please visit: <https://policies.google.com/privacy>
  * Freshmarketer – website tracking and interaction recording. For further information, please visit: <https://www.freshworks.com/freshmarketer-privacy/>

### Deleting cookies

If you would like to restrict the use of cookies you can control this in your Internet browser. Links to advice on how to do this for the most popular Internet browsers are provided below for convenience.

Internet Explorer: <http://windows.microsoft.com/en-GB/windows7/Block-enable-or-allow-cookies>

Google Chrome: [https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en-GB&p=cpn_cookies](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en-GB&p=cpn_cookies)

Firefox: <http://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/Blocking%20cookies>

## Other websites

This website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies.

## Data subject’s rights

As a data subject, you have the following rights, which you can enforce by contacting [DL-CTI-Marketing@capita.co.uk](mailto:DL-CTI-Marketing@capita.co.uk)

### The right to be informed

Capita has an obligation to provide “fair processing information”. We comply with this through this privacy notice which emphasises the need for transparency over how we use personal data.

### The right to access

You have the right to obtain confirmation that your data is being processed and a right to obtain access to your personal data (eg. By receiving a copy of it). We have an obligation to provide this information within 1 month of your request.

### The right to rectification

You have the right to have your personal data rectified if it is inaccurate or incomplete. If Capita TI has provided your details to a third party then we have a requirement to inform them of the rectification where possible

### The right to restrict processing

You have the right to restrict or block processing of your personal data. Where processing has been restricted Capita TI has the right to store the personal data but we are not permitted to process it further. We will retain enough information about you to ensure that restriction is respected in the future.

### The right to erasure (also known as the right to be forgotten)

You have the right to request deletion or removal of your personal data when there is no compelling reason for its continued processing.

### The right to data portability

Data portability allows you the right to obtain and reuse your personal data for your own purpose across different services. It allows you to move, copy or transfer your personal data easily from one IT environment to another in a safe and secure way, without hindrance to usability.

This right only applies to personal data that you have provided to Capita TI as the data controller; where processing is based on your consent or for the performance of a contract; and when processing is carried out by automated means.

### The right to object

You have the right to object to processing based on legitimate interests of the data controller or the performance of a task in the public interest/exercise of official authority; direct marketing (including profiling); and processing for purposes of scientific/ historical research and statistics.

### The right to withdraw consent

If we are processing personal data based on having received your consent you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time.

### The right to complain to a supervisory authority

You have the right to lodge a complaint to the ICO using the following details:

Information Commissioners Office

Wycliffe House  
Water Lane  
Wilmslow  
Cheshire  
SK9 5AF

Tel: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545 745

## Changes to our privacy policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 23 May 2018.
